Contact

Gunnison, CO (925) 964-5104 (Mobile) kyva1500@colorado.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/kyle-vanhoesen-1b552014b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Computer-Aided Design (CAD)
Project Management
Manufacturing

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Sign Languages (Elementary)

Certifications

National Youth Leadership Training CSWA

National Leadership Seminar Leave No Trace Trainer

Honors-Awards

Dean's List

Eagle Scout
Vigil Honor
National Medal of Outdoor
Achievement
Founders Award

Kyle Van Hoesen

Current Student at CU Boulder

Gunnison, Colorado, United States

Summary

I am a mechanical engineer though CU Boulder in conjunction with Western Colorado University. I have lots of experience in mathematics, physics, coding, robotics, GD&T, solidworks CAD, material testing, fabrication, machining, complex system design, and outdoor leadership. I have been extremely involved in Scouts BSA reaching Eagle Scout and Vigil honor in the Order of the Arrow. I am in my last semester of classes before I graduate from CU. I have been focusing my last year of school in robotics, coding, and hands on manufacturing.

Experience

Hustle Bike Labs®
Senior Design Project
August 2022 - Present (7 months)
Gunnison, Colorado, United States

Working with Hustle Bike Labs to create a new pedal. Working with them for senior design though CU boulder. They are fantastic clients to work with and their energy is fantastic. They require hard work but are extremely appreciative and supporting of our team. They also make amazing products I recommend any mountain bikers check them out.

Western Colorado University 2 years

Junior Mountaineer Camp Counselor June 2022 - August 2022 (3 months) Gunnison, Colorado, United States

Supervised other counselors and helped develop science curriculum for the campers. Oversaw teaching of complicated principles of science and engineering to kids 6 to 13 years old.

Teachers Assistant
January 2021 - May 2022 (1 year 5 months)
Gunnison, Colorado, United States

I am a TA for the engineering department. My duties are: Organizing and managing tool crib; Overseeing students and class projects in the Prototyping Lab (mostly 3D printing); Managing woodshop tools and overseeing student projects in the woodshop; Continue education on machine shop tools and equipment.

Supplemental Instructor for Three Engineering Classes January 2021 - May 2021 (5 months)

Gunnison, Colorado, United States

I help teach three engineering classes to other students. I teach Fluid Mechanics, Dynamics, and Mechanics of Solids. I create extra instruction for the students to learn the material if struggling or to enhance their mastering of the subject. The job requires a strong understanding of calculus, physics, statics, engineering, and material science.

Supplemental Instructor for Physics 201 September 2020 - December 2020 (4 months)

Gunnison, Colorado, United States

I help teach calculus-based physics to the students. I attend class and work with the teacher to create extra instruction for the students to learn the material if struggling or to enhance their mastering. The job requires a strong understanding of calculus and physics.

Order of the Arrow BSA
2 years 1 month
Lodge chief of Ut-In Selica
January 2019 - January 2020 (1 year 1 month)
Pleasant Hill, California

I am one of fewer than 300 lodge chiefs who run lodges across the nation. I organize events and oversee all operations of the 500 person lodge. I play an essential part in organizing a multi-lodge event that encompasses a large part of California and most of Nevada. I run monthly meeting with my staff so we can better for-fill the needs of the members of the lodge. I also started a new program for high adventure in the lodge.

Chapter Chief January 2018 - December 2018 (1 year) Mt. Diablo Silvarado Council I was in charge of the meridian district for the BSA honor society. I organize events, run meetings, and work on improving the quality of scouting in the area.

The Athenian School
11 months

Outdoor adventure club leader August 2018 - June 2019 (11 months)

Danville, California

I lead trips for my Highschool and organized meeting for the club. We do trip for all levels so anyone can join with no experience and we help teach them.

Logistics Assistant February 2019 - April 2019 (3 months) Death Valley National Park

For 26 days I was a logistics assistant for a backpacking trip through death valley. the trip had around 50 participants in 5 groups. I helped with resupplies and gear and taught 3 rock climbing clinics. I also fixed broken gear in the field with little equipment.

Teacher Assistant for engineering department August 2018 - December 2018 (5 months) Danville, California

I was a TA for the engineering department at my school and helped maintain the shop, organize equipment, teach simple skills, set up demos for class, prep equipment for class.

Walton woods
Camp Counselor
June 2017 - June 2017 (1 month)
California

I was a camp counselor at a camp for underprivileged children and immigrants. It is run mostly by volunteers and donations so kids who never get to experience the outdoors can come and not worry about paying. I managed a group of kids ageist from 5-12

Education

University of Colorado Boulder

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering , Mechanical Engineering · (2021 - 2023)

Western Colorado University
Bachelor of Science - BS, Mechanical Engineering · (2019 - 2021)

The Athenian School High School Diploma · (2015 - 2019)

Diablo Valley College ASL 1-3, American Sign Language (ASL) · (2016 - 2017)